"Welcome!
"欢迎！
Shoes off please."
请脱鞋。"
In many Asian countries, removing shoes when you enter someone's home is expected – it shows respect and ensures cleanliness.
在许多亚洲国家，进入别人家时脱鞋是惯例——这表示尊重并确保清洁。
In other places, such as the UK, however, the social norms are more ambiguous.
然而，在诸如英国等其他地方，社交规范则更为模糊。
Some Brits might have a strict "shoes off" rule, while others may be squeamish about seeing others' socks or bare feet.
一些英国人可能有严格的"脱鞋"规定，而另一些人则可能对看到别人的袜子或光脚感到不适。
What do the scientists say?
科学家们怎么说呢？
If you remove your shoes at the door for cleanliness, you're probably thinking about the visible dirt – urban dust, mud and grass that has hitched a ride from the outside world on the sole of your shoe.
如果你为了清洁而在门口脱鞋，你可能考虑的是可见的污垢——城市灰尘、泥土和草屑，它们从外界搭便车去到你的鞋底。
But the real problems are microscopic.
但真正的问题是微观层面的。
A review of research called 'Shoe soles as a potential vector for pathogen transmission' found a high prevalence of dangerous bacteria on shoe soles, which could lead to illness.
一项名为《鞋底作为病原体传播的潜在载体》的研究综述发现，鞋底上危险细菌的检出率很高，这可能导致疾病。
Children under five are particularly at risk because of their closeness to the floor and developing immune systems.
尤其五岁以下的儿童风险更大，因为他们离地板很近且免疫系统尚未发育完全。
Germs aside, shoe soles can also bring in nasty chemicals like pesticides and herbicides, exposure to which can cause headaches, dizziness, nausea and vomiting, according to a study by Muhammad Sarwar, published in Cogent Medicine.
除了病菌，鞋底还会带来杀虫剂和除草剂等有害化学物质，根据穆罕默德·萨瓦尔发表在《Cogent医学》上的一项研究，接触这些物质会导致头痛、头晕、恶心和呕吐。
Allergens such as pollen can also enter your home via your shoes, which can be a big issue if you suffer with hay fever or have respiratory issues.
花粉等过敏原也会通过鞋子进入你的家中，如果你患有花粉热或有呼吸系统问题，这可能是一个大问题。
Isn't your home meant to be a safe haven?
你的家难道不应该是一个安全的避风港吗？
But it's not just about hygiene.
但这不仅仅是卫生问题。
Going shoeless can improve things such as balance, body awareness and strength and stability in your muscles, according to a medically reviewed article called 'Does Walking Barefoot Have Health Benefits?'.
根据一篇经过医学评审的文章《赤脚走路对健康有益吗？》，不穿鞋可以改善平衡、身体意识以及肌肉的力量和稳定性。"
"In theory, walking barefoot more closely restores our 'natural' walking pattern, also known as our gait," explains foot and ankle specialist Jonathan Kaplan.
理论上，赤脚走路更能恢复我们'自然的'步行模式，也就是我们的步态，"足踝专家乔纳森·卡普兰解释道。
In cultures where a shoe-free home is the norm, the reasons are backed by science.
在以不穿鞋进屋为常态的文化中，这些原因是有科学依据的。
And in places where the rules are less clear, maybe it's time to think about leaving our outdoor shoes at the threshold.
在规则不那么明确的地方，也许是时候考虑把我们的户外鞋留在门槛处了。
There's an old African proverb that states "When you leave your shoes at the doorstep, you leave your troubles behind."
有一句古老的非洲谚语说："当你在门阶上脱下鞋子时，你就把烦恼留在了身后。"